Roberto Jose Cardenas

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | robertocardenas@berkeley.edu | Oakland, CA

SUMMARY

Food service industry professional who is educated as a Computer Scientist that is looking to restart his career as a developer. Has 2 years of professional experience as a Full Stack Developer and is extremely passionate about websites and code that are beautifully designed and executed.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sous Chef, Cellarmaker Brewing Company

March 2024 – Ongoing

- Manage kitchen operations, including inventory, prep list creation, quality control, and closing
- Maintain good communication with the front of house staff, relaying all food items we are out of, menu changes and delays as needed

AM Kitchen Lead, Cellarmaker Brewing Company

September 2023– March 2024

 Planned out and managed the execution and completion of daily and weekly production goals for both of the restaurant locations

Kitchen Manager, Berkeley Student Cooperative

Aug 2021 – May 2023

 Managed the purchasing, receiving, stocking, inventory and budgeting of all food and supplies for the 124 resident unit

Full Stack Developer, Motus

June 2018 – January 2021

- Designed and developed two customer-facing full stack web applications, planning out and executing the development of relational databases, API's, CMS's and user clients for each project
- Collaborated with the company designer to create and prototype responsive layouts and translated them into production code
- Collaborated with other teams to create tools for accessing and modifying shared project data
- Maintained and updated legacy projects by refactoring the codebase and creating documentation

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: PHP, HTML, CSS (SCSS), MySQL, JavaScript (JQuery), Java, Python (Flask), Ruby (Rails), git, GitHub, VSCode, Figma, PHPMyAdmin, Composer
- Attention to detail
- Ability to work under pressure and changing expectations
- Project management

PROJECTS

Waste Information Website, August 2021

• Designed and implemented a web application utilizing ReactJS to educate residents on proper waste disposal, including a user facing web client, an API and CMS to ensure future updates could be made easily

End-to-end Encrypted File Sharing System, December 2020

- Designed and implemented a Go client application to share files securely, factoring in adversaries/malicious users and untrusted public file servers
- Supported multiple user sessions, sharing and revoking user privileges, and efficient file modification

PintOS, August 2020

- Designed and implemented a uniprocessor OS in a team of 4
- Implemented thread polls and scheduling, user programs and protection, growable file systems and file cache, and multiple system calls

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, CSS Fundamentals, Modern Web Design, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Security, Operating Systems and Systems Programming, Database Systems